MAURICIO SEBASTIAN GUERRA GARCIA

sebastianguerra122@gmail.com 0435 512 111 LinkedIn

Profile

Monash University – Master of Data Science graduate driven by data to make decisions. Use of data becomes more and more important so data visualization, data analysis and machine learning are aspects I've focused over past years. I have worked in transnational companies with fast-paced environments, multicultural teams, and under pressure to achieve goals within a deadline. I'm looking forward to using the skills I've gained to make a difference in the technological world.

Academic Background

2019 - 2020

Master of Data Science- Monash University

Key projects:

- TeenEx- Industry experience project utilizing open data to build an IT for good solution, utilizing Wordpress and Tableau.
- Image and text classification with Keras Tensorflow
- Tweet gender classification utilizing machine learning and natural language processing
- Australian bushfire prediction with machine learning
- MINST dataset image classification with deep learning techniques with Keras Tensorflow

2017

Demand Planning Certification- Florida State University

Key Aspects:

- Linear Regression for SKU demands
- Calculated optimal SKU inventory base on demand
- Statistical analysis for demand planning

2012 - 2017

Bachelor in Science- Universidad del Valle de Guatemala

2012 - 2016

Industrial Engineer, High Distinction- Universidad del Valle de Guatemala

Professional Experience

Mar 2019 - Present

The Big Group- Hospitality

Position: Event Waiter in catering company.

Highlight events: September Club, Australian Open, and Melbourne Cup.

- Offered exceptional customer service meeting client needs
- Delivering service in events for over 1000+ people
- Assisted supervisor in problem solving
- Communicating to client for serving food and drinks
- Proactive problem-solving unexpected issues

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

CBC (PepsiCo's Bottling Company)

Position: Logistics Coordinator

- Coordinated Just-In-Time delivery for finish product within Guatemala, fleet size over 150
- Coordinated transportation for exports, over 30 daily trucks
- Analysed transportation costs and implemented saving schemes
- Worked on SAP Transport Management implementation
- Worked on yearly budget forecast
- Redefined department KPI's for better control
- Achieved export process quality certification for faster export times
- Team leader which involves coordinating daily functions of a team of 100 people

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

CBC (PepsiCo's Bottling Company)

Position: Trainee

- Trained on whole systematic company vision
- Rotated through manufacturing, commercial, logistics, and corporative areas to learn interaction and role within each other
- Last 6 months got exposed to key logistic positions for a better formation within the company

Mar 2016 - Nov 2016

Colgate

Position: Marketing Internship

- Led marketing campaigns for toothbrush and toothpaste segments for Central America
- Led biggest AAA campaign for new product launch in 5 countries
- Detected low sale segments and implemented action plans
- Used Tableau to keep track of KPI's and addition of new dashboards
- Analysed data market insights for segment targeting for better sales across product categories
- Achieved sales KPI's such as share of market and total revenue

2010 - 2014

Medegua- Dental Equipment Retail Store

Position: Attendant & Salesperson

- Offered exceptional customer service in showroom floor, more than 20 customers per day
- Expanded portfolio of existing clients by providing new equipment & maintenance
- Engaged into administrative tasks such as inventory count, organizing client visits and placing purchasing orders
- Coordinated follow-ups on client's sales and maintenance for recurrent purchases
- General Sales

Software Knowledge and Skills

Languages- Python, SQL, R, HTML, Javascript

Operating Systems- Windows, Linux

Software- Advanced Excel, PowerPoint, Word, Tableau, SAP, SPSS

Skills- Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Pandas, NLP, Scikit Learn, R Shiny, D3,

Hobbies and interests

Ex Guatemalan Nacional Baseball Team Player 2003-2015

Member of Monash Baseball Team

Albert Park Soccer

Running- Aiming for first marathon

Volunteering

2011-2017

Techo Para Mi Pais (Roof For Guatemala)

Built sustainable houses for low income people without proper living conditions

2015

Community tree planting

Aid planting over 2000 trees to reforest damaged areas by woodcutting

2016

Primary School volunteering

Helped overhaul kitchens menu having healthier and cheaper alternatives for kids

2019

Monash Post Graduate Association

Volunteered for events helping new students get more familiar with Melbourne

References

Available upon request